<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Knowledge-Driven Applications | Manling Li</title>
    <link>https://limanling.github.io/tag/knowledge-driven-applications/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://limanling.github.io/tag/knowledge-driven-applications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Knowledge-Driven Applications</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://limanling.github.io/media/icon_hu437e05b1b543de801281f81b261d0785_1145_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Knowledge-Driven Applications</title>
      <link>https://limanling.github.io/tag/knowledge-driven-applications/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write: SmartBook</title>
      <link>https://limanling.github.io/researchsummary/smartbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://limanling.github.io/researchsummary/smartbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the main bottlenecks of large corpora analysis is the multi-document encoding. Whereas existing
studies have built text graphs by augmenting text sequences with different hidden structural information,
they are typically entity-centric and overlook the events’ intra-structures (arguments) and inter-structures
(event-event connections).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My solution is using event graphs to provide a new comprehensive representation and necessary
inductive bias. I propose to define the multi-document joint representation as the contextualized
embeddings of the nodes on the event graph and collectively model events and arguments. These event
graphs can then be used to address the massive unstructured data challenge in real-world applications:
(1) Timeline Summarization is formulated as an event graph compression problem and then I
design time-aware optimal transport to obtain the summary graph. (2) Meeting Summarization
leverages agenda-based topics to segment meeting transcripts, and takes advantage of multi-modal
sensing of the meeting environment, such as cameras to capture each participant’s head pose and eye
gaze. (3) Multimedia News Question Answering employs multimedia event graphs to condition
synthetic question-answer generation, and to automatically augment data via weak supervision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My work is the first study to use event graph representations to overcome fundamental challenges in
handling massive unstructured data that exist in various applications. It provides tangible guidelines to
use event structural knowledge in practice, and shows positive results on long-standing open problems
in event tracking&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
